we're gonna do the 13-point meditation
let me get it and several people asked
me they want to do more projects and
like Stanley you want to do more
projects but they also feel very busy
and they feel a lot of pressure so they
want to know how can I do more projects
for cash in mind and how can I not feel
stressed you know how can I do more
things for people but inside it become
more peaceful okay so we're gonna do
Tomlin for this is how to do okay we
have to do Tomlin for busy people
somebody who's busy very busy because we
want to do a lot of good things for
people but we also want to be peaceful
we don't want to feel stressed and then
the meditation won't go well and you
can't see emptiness okay so we want to
do both right in English with America we
say yeah I want my cake and I want to
eat the cake also okay so I would like
to be very busy right yummy and do big
projects 6000 people come to the talk
but also I like in my personal life I
like to be super peaceful and calm and I
don't feel stressed okay
so we're gonna do this kind of tumbling
this morning with the 13 steps okay cool
I think all of us need this I need also
so the best way to get more time and the
best way to get more peaceful at the
same time is sticked on man with a mama
and with exchanging okay good
all right so get ready if you want to
record this okay if you forget to take
your phone our cell we will donate to
Diamond Mountain just kidding Mayo Mayo
amendment booyah we are moment okay here
we go
small smile keep that smile all the way
to China
okay on the plane relax your eyelids
relax your hands stomach
pulled in a little bit the feeling in
this room right now it feels good I'm
happy about your meditation you had a
good retreat it's like you're at level 9
and your eyelid closed and it got very
quiet here most people so I think you
had a good retreat
please come again it's good to have a
break in your life now let's do 10 slow
breaths long out-breath and put your
mind on your breath like you put your
hand on your pillow
then we're going to do the 13 part
meditation and this means we're also
going to do Tomlin with someone maybe
not very close to us so not your family
not your close friends but maybe
somebody you work with maybe somebody
I'm thinking in my business as supplier
or an employee someone I'm not that
close to them it's not my family
not my close friend but we are trying to
reach a feeling of equal treat other
people equal the people I know and the
people I don't know so well
and today this Tomlin is special Tomlin
to plant the seeds to be able to do big
projects to be able to be busy helping
people all of our projects are helping
people our work our businesses are also
helping people many people are helping
with many good projects John Brady's
project to save ancient wisdom projects
to help children in Mexico and there are
many projects and today the meditation
is how can I be very busy and do big
projects and at the same time
those projects are growing and growing
but at the same time my meditation is
going deeper and deeper at the same time
that I have more and more things to do I
feel more and more relaxed
I don't feel busy
I don't feel stressed I'm doing big
projects I'm helping many people I'm
working to make money and take care of
my family but at the same time my inner
feeling is more and more relaxed more
and more happy I don't feel nervous
I don't feel stress you can give me more
projects and my meditation will go
deeper and deeper and that will feel
more and more relaxed it seems
impossible but as we learned from the
gardener all things are coming from
seeds so if we plant the seeds with
Tommen it would be possible to do many
projects for people and take care of my
family take care of my business but at
the same time my meditation can get
deeper and deeper and actually I feel
more and more relaxed I feel more open
space in my mind I don't feel busy
so choose a person step number one of
the 13 steps choose a person in your
life someone you're not too close to but
who's very busy we all know some busy
people the person who does the plumbing
on my house the person who fixes the
water taps and faucets and he's very
very busy I don't know him very well I
almost I don't know his name but I know
he's extremely busy he never has time
and he always has a lot of stress so
maybe I will choose this person for
tonglen he's not close to me he's not my
family
he's not my close friend but I know his
life is very very busy and he has a lot
of stress family stress also okay here
we go you choose somebody
because the mind has a cause because
this moment of my mind came from
yesterday's mine and yesterday's mine
came from mine before and chemicals
cannot actually make awareness there are
different stuff different substance
therefore my mind has always existed in
this universe I have been to countless
lives and this plumber that I'm thinking
about he has been my mom many times it's
very strange to think of this old
plumber guy that I came out of his body
and he happily took the truck pain
suffering a birth to give me life and it
feels very strange to imagine I am
drinking milk from his breath in my past
life and it feels strange to think he is
feeding me very carefully very patiently
over and over giving me soft food then
teaching me how to poopoo it's very
strange to think my plumber this old
plumber who comes to my house he cleaned
the poopoo from my body many times and
work to give me clothes when I was a
child
took me to school gave me love so
imagine this person has been your mom
think about what they did for you
after that third step of thinking about
what they did for us the fourth step of
course if someone spent many years of
their life sacrifice their life which
all mothers do sacrifice their time
didn't have any free time didn't have
any time to relax or to rest they did
all these things for me for many years
and of course it would be so nice now I
am grown up I'm not a child anymore and
at some time in our life all of us began
to think oh my mom she spent so many
hours of her life she gave me so much of
her life
sacrificed her life for me then I should
do something to help her so step 4
oh I should do something to pay her back
my plumber mom I should I I should take
responsibility I if I'm a good person
and she gave me so much love so many
years of her life at least I can help
her a little bit my old plumber mom
then sometimes we feel how I I'm very
busy I don't have time to take care of
this old plumber I it's difficult for me
to have time to take care of myself
and I cannot get money to everyone who
needs money
I need for myself and that's true we
have to eat we have to have a place to
live but so does my mom
plumber she also needs a place to live
she also needs money I should be equal
we have equal right everybody
appreciates equal rights in every
country every person should have equal
chance equal opportunity equal rights to
be happy so if I'm a good person I
should agree the plumber mom she has him
equal right to me to my money to my time
she has equal right I'm not more
important than her we are equally
important
in my whole life this is step 6 my whole
life I've been focusing on myself making
money for myself feeding myself combing
my hair buying clothes for me my whole
life I've been taking care of this body
but in the end it doesn't mean much this
body will get all this body already
probably has several diseases one of
them will kill me so to spend all my
time taking care of this body which will
fail it will break one day it will be
finished then why spend so much time on
one body that won't stay very long
why not give my help to other people
it's strange that I take care of one
body and that body won't last it's it's
strange I will spend all my effort on
one body
then I can think about how beautiful it
is when I take care of other people this
is step 7 if the seeds are true then the
way to make myself happy in the way to
get everything anyone is to pay more
attention to what other people need I
don't have to ignore myself I also have
equal right so it's not a sacrifice I
I'm not stop eating and I don't stop
buying things for myself
let's buy nice things for myself and my
family that's good
but let's also give some time to buying
things for other people who I don't know
so much and making sure everybody has
food if I happily in a relaxed way I buy
things for myself and I take money for
myself but I also share with other
people then it's such a nice way of life
the more I share the more I have for
myself and my family this is a nice
sister it's fun to take care of other
people it makes everyone happy and
relaxed and at the same time I will have
more to help my family so let me take
of all these other people yet the
plumber is very stressed out then let me
go and talk to him when he comes to my
house give him a nice coffee tell him to
sit down and relax with me take my time
to make him relax if I do that if I take
this little time for others for my mom
this system is so cool I will have more
time for myself someone will give me
time and I can do more projects and I
can be more and more relaxed
you
step 8 it's kind of the logical
discussion to myself if I don't want to
be so busy the old logic says oh I
should do last things I should not take
care of other people I don't have time
it would be nice but I don't have time I
have to do less things I have to do
fewer things that's the old logic new
logic time comes from giving time to
other people sit down relax ask the
plumber my mom when he comes to my house
then take the time sit down talk about
his family talk about his life listen
give him some rest
give him some relaxation give him my
time and this new system is so cool
because every minute I give to him I'm
getting 10 minutes back
step 9
I imagine how I look to him oh this guy
I don't know him very well his name is
Mike I work at his house sometimes he
used to ignore me he was very busy on
his computer and he is to come to work
at his house and he never had time to
talk to me but now a strange he seems to
be more relaxing he takes the time to
offer me a coffee and we sit down and he
listens to me I feel more relaxed when I
go through his house he seems to care
about me go into the other person's body
and look at yourself and see that change
the improvement of this person they are
so calm and they are so willing to give
me some time to talk about my life
now imagine how the busy feeling they
have stressed too many things to do in
their heart in the mom plumber heart
this person I don't know very well but
try to imagine all the stress they have
they also have many things to do they
also feel like they never have enough
time they also feel nervous many times
all that feeling stress collects in
their heart like a black smoke
didn't we think or I would take that I
will help you I will take away your
stress even if the stress has to come to
me I will take away your stress you have
been my mom many times I would be a very
strange person if I didn't help my mom
each time you breathe in let the black
smoke come out of their heart out of
their North and comes to the in front of
your nose didn't check your heart inside
your heart is a beautiful lotus flower
pink color saw very subtle but very good
smell
and inside the petals resting in the
middle is a diamond you can imagine a
meditation ring with a big piece of
diamond
the diamond is here wisdom of
understanding emptiness husband in the
kitchen the lordís is your love your
dumb man and make a decision I will take
away your stress even if it has to come
to me I will take it away because you
you are my mom you gave me so much and
on the count of three we will breathe in
this moment and this joy in one breath
never more than one breath one two and
three and the smoke touches the diamond
and there's a flash like lightning and
the smoke is destroyed like small
cigarette smoking and it goes away
you're busy plumber friend mom all the
stress they feel suddenly they don't
feel so nervous suddenly they don't feel
so busy suddenly they don't feel so much
stressed they don't know why and that's
a sort of nice that the child will take
away the pain of the mom without asking
and without telling the mom they just
take care of it
this is a good boy good girl it takes
care of mom doesn't even tell the mom so
you can feel happy that you destroyed
your mom's
let's give her some relaxation breathe
out from that beautiful Lotus some
golden light and it goes to her nose she
breathes in this golden light and it
totally relaxed it doesn't mean she has
less things to do it doesn't mean she's
not busy but it means her feeling has
changed she feels calm even when things
are very busy even when there's a lot of
stress she feels confident and she feels
relaxed and she's able to do many things
without stress
step 12 I will take care of you don't
worry each time I see you even in my
meditation mr. plumber mom I'm the one
person you can count on in your life I
know you have friends I know you have
family I know you work with other people
I know you don't know me very well but
anonymously without telling anybody I
will take care of you in this life and
in many future lives I will be there to
help you I am your good son I'm your
good daughter you can trust me I will
take care of you
I make a commitment step 12 personal
responsibility
step thirteen I would be responsible
person among all people I will be that
good example for everyone anyone who
meets me even at the store or in the
airport who doesn't know me they will
feel something strange feeling from me
I'm very calm I'm very happy I'm care
about the people around me I have some
special love for those people even
people who don't know me in the airport
in the plane in the grocery store they
feel inspired something special about me
what is that is I spent my morning
meditating to serve other people to help
other people my method of living is to
take other people's stress and take
other people's busyness and offer them a
coffee a few minutes to talk about
themselves they're loyal I will I will
be the one who listens I will be a body
sir
there's a in the body stuff about
ceremony there's a beautiful verse now
my life has meaning before my life what
didn't have much meaning but now I'm but
I saw I committed to do this meditation
I committed to take care of all my moms
and now my life has meaning now there's
a purpose to my life my life wasn't
wasted
good job any questions about that
meditation no Janice has a question is
there microphone thank you for the
lovely meditation guy Sheila my question
is why do we just do it for just one
person and not switch and bring in
another one and why not what well you
said to just do the meditation just keep
it on one person oh yeah yeah so I was
wondering why oh you can I mean after
you learn to eat one - no you can eat
two so so it's generally when we
meditate we start with one person and
later you can try more but the idea is
if you become an example with one person
then automatically you will you will
serve others okay we there's a famous
question in I think it's in shantideva
it's can I pay the bills of every person
in the world and the answer is not right
now so they say pay the bills of one
person okay and that's a good example
and then maybe other people will pay
other people's bills and so it there's a
discussion oh it's in the opening lines
of Dharma Quixote from Antarctica you
know is it even possible to take care of
everyone's bills and I have to say no I
mean even words bills cost me so much so
not possible but
if I try to become a good example for
other people then then I can take care
of other people's bills through through
my thousand arms
it means through the people who see my
example okay then I can grow a thousand
arms okay if I'm just a good example for
one plumber
okay so ya work with one person and
don't be impatient okay
don't don't be impatient with yourself
don't say I'm a bad person I'm only
helping one person don't think like that
if you have one mom very well then other
people will look at you and they say oh
wow that's cool I like to do that I
would like to try that
Yali is so busy but she's so calm she
never gets stressed out and yell at
people and they will they will use that
example and then they become your arm
other people become your arms then you
have a thousand arts okay any other
questions thank you guys over for
meditation I have a question which is
indirectly related to meditation so I've
met you just two years ago in September
2017 and the first time I've heard about
pen in July 2017 from Anton Trotter sook
he told me about it and then it just
happened that I don't know why my
company decided to send me to give to do
some project exactly the same time when
this a7 was in Kiev so and it was first
time when I met you and the since then
that incredible things happening with me
and think that I couldn't even dream of
and I couldn't even
and uses four steps to get because they
are so cool I couldn't even dream in the
useful steps so my question is get
shallow what's going on
am i just using my good seats a bank
account what's happening is so cool I
can't even dream about yeah there's a
DCI teaching called don't try to guess
there's a nice DCI teaching corner don't
try to guess it means if you because the
Karma double every 24 hours because I
see double every 24 hours then in one
month that's a million that becomes one
seed at the first of the month becomes 1
million at the end of the month it's
like a very bad credit card the interest
discovery card you you buy one dollar
thing in the first of the month and by
the end of the month you or $1,000,000
but it's a good it's a good interest
rate right you get more good so I think
you know sometimes it's good not to
limit your goal okay don't say oh I want
to make you know extra hundred dollars
or extra thousand dollars just sometimes
it's good to say I will plant the money
seed and then let's see what happens you
know I will do lots of coffee meditation
and that guy who made ten million
dollars Shanghai in one year maybe he
could make a hundred million my diamond
company we start with a half a table we
rent half a table we cannot afford the
hotel
in the other guy's office I remember his
name is Alex Rosenthal and we ran to
half his table we rent half table in one
room and we don't even have permission
to use the toilet
we have to go to the McDonald's and
peepee you know he won't give us the key
to the toilet he said you're not paying
for 20 you know and we have three
diamonds and there's three people and
it's kind of strange company we are
moving the diamond around on the table
did you get any call for diamond no
let's check it again someday we don't
have any work no we don't sell anything
and we just sit there and try to find
customer we cannot imagine that if we we
use the money for jumbo dispersion we
give the money my profit we give to John
Brady's project we cannot imagine
someday we will do 300,000 diamonds
every day 300,000 times every day you
know we cannot imagine we will be the
largest diamond company joint diamond
jewelry company in the world we cannot
even if you ask me when we have a half a
table and no place to pee pee what's
your goal I would say all we want to
sell ten dollars you know
so trust the Karma okay and don't put on
don't put a lemon on it and keep doing
this meditation okay that's a big
machine for success okay all right